Guide to Elizabeth Baldwin Literary Society records, 1924-1984 UA 289
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Elizabeth Baldwin Literary Society records
1924-1984
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Elizabeth Baldwin Literary Society
UA 289
21 Linear Feet 2 boxes and 4 oversize boxes
The Elizabeth Baldwin Literary Society (EBLS) was founded in 1914 and named in honor of the second wife of William Marsh Rice. It was an active organization until the mid 1980s. In 1919, the literary society split to form another society, the Pallas Athene Literary Society (PALS). In 1924, an alumnae group for EBLS was formed. The records contain correspondence, scrapbooks, newsclippings regarding activities, programs from plays performed by the society, as well as correspondence and directories from the alumnae group.
Historical Note
The Elizabeth Baldwin Literary Society (EBLS) was founded in 1914 and named in honor of the second wife of William Marsh Rice. It was an active organization until the mid 1980s. In 1919, the literary society split to form another society, the Pallas Athene Literary Society (PALS). In 1924, an alumnae group for EBLS was formed.
Scope and Contents
The records contain correspondence, scrapbooks, newsclippings regarding activities, programs from plays performed by the society, as well as correspondence and directories from the alumnae group.
Access Restrictions
This material is open for research.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored offsite at the Library Service Center and require 24-hour notice for retrieval. Please contact the Woodson Research Center at 713-348-2586 or woodson@rice.edu for more information.
Acquisition Information
Donations from members Charlotte Talbot, E. Pender Turnbull, Joyce Nagle, Karen Rogers.
Index Terms
Subjects
Universities and colleges; Literature -- Societies, etc.; Rice University -- History; Women
Document Types
clippings (information artifacts); photographs; corrrespondence; directories
- Series I: Administrative, 1924-1984, 146304
  - Correspondence, 1924-1984, n.d.; 146305 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, incoming, 1943-1948; 146306 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Directories, 1949/1949 - 1957/58; 146307 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Directory - with items addressed to E. Pender Turnbull, 1958/1959; 146308 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Directory - with notes and E. Pender Turnbull bookmark, 1959/1960; 146309 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Directories, 1960/61 - 1967/68; 146310 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Directory - with items addressed to E. Pender Turnbull, 1960/1961; 146311 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Meeting Notes, Minutes, Membership Lists, 1970-1979; 146312 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Meeting Notes, Minutes, Membership Lists, 1980-1984; 146313 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Constitutions, 1952-1955, n.d.; 146314 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Contracts, 1957-1976; 146315 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Series II: Newsclippings, 1924-1972, 146316
  - Newsclippings, 1924-1940; 146317 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Newsclippings, 1944-1959; 146318 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Newsclippings, 1960-1972; 146319 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Newsclippings, n.d.; 146320 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Series III: Academics, Alumnae, and Events, 1925-1982, 146321
  - Academics, 1925-1956; 146322 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Alumnae, 1924-1976, n.d.; 146323 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Event Programs, Signs, and Invitations, 1930-1982, n.d.; 146324 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Party Invitation on Pillow Case, n.d.; 146325 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Play Programs, 1955-1966, n.d.; 146326 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Alice in Wonderland Script, 146327 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - De Pelchin Faith Home and Children's Bureau, 1942, 1944; 146328 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Series IV: Photographs and Scrapbooks, 1937-1983, 146329
  - Photographs, 1975-1983, n.d.; 146330 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Loose Materials - Scrapbook, 1937-1945; 146331 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Loose Materials - Scrapbook, 1949; 146332 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Loose Materials - Scrapbook, 1952-1953; 146333 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Loose Materials - Scrapbook, 1954-1955; 146334 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Loose Materials - Scrapbook, 1960-1964; 146335 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Loose Materials - Scrapbook, 1964-1965; 146336 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Scrapbook, 1938-1942; 146337 (Box 3, Folder -)
  - Scrapbook, 1945-1950; 146338 (Box 3, Folder -)
  - Scrapbook, 1942-1948; 146339 (Box 3, Folder -)
  - 1 Scrapbook Sheet, 1944-1945; 146340 (Box 3, Folder -)
  - 2 Scrapbook Sheets, 1943; 146341 (Box 3, Folder -)
  - Scrapbook, 1947-1948; 146342 (Box 4, Folder -)
  - Scrapbook, 1949; 146343 (Box 4, Folder -)
  - Scrapbook, 1950-1951; 146344 (Box 4, Folder -)
  - Scrapbook, 1951-1952; 146345 (Box 4, Folder -)
  - Scrapbook, 1952-1953; 146346 (Box 4, Folder -)
  - Scrapbook, 1960-1961; 146347 (Box 5, Folder -)
  - Scrapbook, 1964-1965; 146348 (Box 5, Folder -)
  - Scrapbook, 1969-1970; 146349 (Box 5, Folder -)
  - Scrapbook, 1971-1972; 146350 (Box 6, Folder -)